<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Advertisement. At the Hand and Pen near the King's Bagnio in Long-Acre, liveth Mrs. Isabella Inglish, who alone is authorised by their Majesties to make and publish Dr. Anderson's Grana Angelica, or the famous true Scots Pills ...</title>
            <author>Inglish, Isabella.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 5KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B24624</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99888611</idno>
  <idno type="VID">195836</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2248544816</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing I187B</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide C.112.f.9[31]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R231269</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99888611</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99888611e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B24624)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 195836)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; E8:1[31])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Advertisement. At the Hand and Pen near the King's Bagnio in Long-Acre, liveth Mrs. Isabella Inglish, who alone is authorised by their Majesties to make and publish Dr. Anderson's Grana Angelica, or the famous true Scots Pills ...</title>
                  <author>Inglish, Isabella.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1690]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Imprint information from Wing.</note>
                  <note>Title taken from caption and first lines of text.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="personal_name">Anderson, Patrick, fl. 1618-1635.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Advertising --  Drugs --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Medicine --  Formulae, receipts, prescriptions --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Broadsides --  England --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-04 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-10 </date>
            <label>Simon Charles </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-10 </date>
            <label>Simon Charles</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="advert_for_quack_medicines">
            <pb facs="tcp:195836:1"/>
            <head>ADVERTISEMENT.</head>
            <p>At the <hi>Hand and Pen</hi> near the King's <hi>Bagnio</hi> in <hi>Long-Acre,</hi> liveth Mrs. <hi>Isabella Inglish,</hi> who alone is Authorised by their MAJESTIES, to Make and Publish</p>
            <p>DR. <hi>ANDERSON's GRANA ANGELICA, or the famous true SCOTS PILLS;</hi> so universally known and approved by Physicians and others of all Ranks, for their rare and singular Virtues; And particularly, as a very Soveraign Remedy against <hi>Diseases or Pains in the Head, Stomach, or Bellies</hi> of Men, Women and Children; but especially against <hi>Giddiness</hi> and <hi>Megrims, Deafness, weak or bleared Eyes, Want of Appetite, Choller, Melancholly, Phlegm, Gross</hi> and <hi>thick Humors, Worms, Paleness, Green-Sickness, Defluctions</hi> on the <hi>Lungs</hi> or <hi>Joynts, Gravel, Stone, Scurvy, Dropsie, Chollick</hi> or <hi>Gripes, and all Obstructions,</hi> and the most effectual Medicine for those who are <hi>Costive.</hi> They are so accommodated to all <hi>Ages, Seasons</hi> or <hi>Hours,</hi> that they are safely used by Women with Child, <hi>Infants,</hi> or <hi>Decrepit Old</hi> Persons. <hi>Summer</hi> or <hi>Winter,</hi> at any <hi>Time</hi> of the Day, without Regard to <hi>Diet,</hi> or Hindrance of <hi>Business.</hi> Their Operation is so gentle, pleasant, and effectual, that by Experience they are found to exceed any Medicine hitherto published. The Dose is from 3 to 11, as may be seen more at large in my Papers of Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rections given with the said Pills.</p>
            <p>That which sufficiently demonstrates their Excellency, is the Multitude of Counterfeits, some pretending to have them from <hi>Scotland,</hi> whereas none has been prepared there of late years; so that many Persons of Quality, and of the more Intelligent of that Kingdom, have them from me, as being assured of their due Preparation; and yet some of the Pretenders from thence, as <hi>broken Merchants, Ignorant Tradesmen, and scandalous Persons,</hi> &amp;c. have the Confidence to impose upon the People, endeavoring to settle a Correspondence by such as themselves here, for vend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing their counterfeit Pills.</p>
            <p>Others, and particularly one <hi>MOGSON,</hi> of late, by his Advertisements, pretends to have had the Receipt from Mrs. <hi>Katharine Anderson,</hi> as being intimately acquainted with her in <hi>Scot<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land;</hi> and hath had the Impudence to counterfeit my <hi>Printed Directions</hi> Verbatim, and my <hi>Sign</hi> and <hi>Seal,</hi> giving out that they are only prepared by him; the Vanity of which Pretences will forthwith appear to every thinking and unprejudiced Person, if they consider that it's now a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bout ten years since Mrs. <hi>Anderson</hi>'s Death, during which time he never pretended to any such thing, whereas I have prepared these Pills ever since; Nor can he make appear he was ever in <hi>Scotland,</hi> as he falsly pretends: Nay so little Truth is in his Assertions, that in <hi>March</hi> last, he himself did meet with me, at Mr. <hi>Lloyd</hi>'s Coffee-house in <hi>Lombard-Street,</hi> and desired him to vend my Pills there, but since then, <hi>he hath trick'd him and me both, which can and may perhaps be made appear in as publick a manner as he hath made himself a Lyar, to the View of the World by his Counterfeit Sign,</hi> &amp;c. But to put this out of all doubt, I offer to prove, as I have already done before the <hi>King's Physicians,</hi> that the said <hi>MOGSON,</hi> discovered the Cheat himself on the 16th of <hi>September</hi> last, to two Gentlemen, to whom (contrary to his Print) he pretended that he was intimately acquainted with Dr. <hi>Anderson</hi> at <hi>Edenburgh,</hi> who admitted him into his <hi>Closet,</hi> whence he <hi>stole</hi> the said Receipt out of a Book of the Doctor's: Whereas the said Doctor has been dead above 50 years, being long before <hi>MOGSON</hi> was born. And he did also acknow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledge to the same Gentlemen, that his Pills were not the same with Dr. <hi>Anderson</hi>'s.</p>
            <p>To prevent Abuses and Dangers which may ensue from such Counterfeits, I have (by Their MAJESTIES Order) published the said Pills frequently in the <hi>Gazette,</hi> and am also advised to give Notice in this manner: That Dr. <hi>Anderson</hi>'s, or the Scots Pills, are only truly and faithfully made by Mrs. <hi>Isabella Inglish</hi> (with the Care and Inspection of her Husband Mr. <hi>Ja. Inglish,</hi> Philo-Chymist) who alone is authorised by Their MAJESTIES to prepare and publish the same; and lives at the <hi>Hand and Pen</hi> near the King's <hi>Bagnio</hi> in <hi>Long-Acre, London.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>